爸爸？
Papa?
我两个儿子都死了
Both my sons are dead.
生命中只有两种悲剧
There are only two tragedies in life.
得不到你要的，跟得到你要的
One is not getting what you want. The other is getting it.
这是你卖的吗？
ls this one of yours?
瓦伦亭终于一偿夙愿
Jack Valentine finally had what he wanted.
死亡证明说他死于心脏衰竭
Curiously, the death certificate says he died of heart failure.
你是说我假造死亡证明？
Falsifying a death certificate?
那也扳不倒我
That's not gonna hold me.
没错，你又对了
You're right. As usual, you are right.
有看今天的报纸吗？
Have you seen today's paper? Huh?
致命武器交付监管
Fake end-user certificates.
伪造使用者证明、虚设行号
Cut-out companies, meticulously catalogued.
世界各地军阀、独裁者…
There is hardly a warlord, dictator, despot anywhere in the world
暴君，无不跟你称兄道弟
that you're a first-name basis with.
你视为战利品的太太泄底的
It was your wife your trophy wife that led us to the prize.
不是她的错，她比较好跟踪
It's not her fault. She's just easier to follow than you are.
我可以看吗？
May l?
请便
Yeah, go ahead.
慢慢享用
Enjoy it.
- 什么  - 这个
- What?  - This.
我是你所有厌恶事物的化身
Tell me I'm everything you despise.
邪恶的代言人
That I'm the personification of evil.
我应该为社会组织和…
What?
世界秩序崩溃负责
responsible for the breakdown of the fabric of society and world order.
我是种族灭绝的幕后推手
I'm a one-man genocide.
想说什么现在都说出来
Say everything you want to say to me now.
因为你的时间不多
Because you don't have long.
你是清醒的，还是在妄想？
Are you paying attention? or are you delusional?
你破坏所有武器禁运条约
You have broken every arms embargo written.
你的罪证…
There is enough here to
足以判下好几个无期徒刑
put you away for consecutive life sentences.
在正式入狱服刑前…
You are going to spend the next ten years of your life
光跑法院就得耗上十年
going from a cell to a courtroom before you even start serving your time.
我想你还不了解你的处境
I don't think you fully appreciate the seriousness... ...of your situation.
我的家人不要我
My family has disowned me.
我太太和儿子抛弃我
My wife and son have left me.
我弟弟死了
My brother's dead.
相信我，我完全了解…
Trust me.
我的处境有多危险
I fully appreciate the seriousness of my situation.
但我向你保证…
But I promise you,
我不会花一秒钟在法庭
I won't spend a single second in a courtroom.
你在妄想
You are delusional.
我也不喜欢你，杰克
I like you, Jack.
或许喜欢，但我了解你
Well, maybe not, but I understand you.
我跟你说会发生什么事
Let me tell you what's gonna happen.
让你好及早做准备
This way, you can prepare yourself.
好吧
Okay.
很快会有人来敲门叫你出去
Soon there's going to be a knock on that door and you will be called outside.
大厅有个比你高阶的人
ln the hall there will be a man who outranks you.
首先他会恭维你立了大功…
First, he'll compliment you on the fine job you've done
世界因为你变得更安全
that you're making the world a safer place
你将获得表扬与升迁
that you're to receive a commendation and a promotion.
接着他说我会被释放
And then he'll tell you that I am to be released.
你抗议
You're gonna protest.
可能还威胁要辞职
You'll probably threaten to resign.
但最后我还是会被释放
But in the end, I will be released.
我被释放的理由跟你认为…
The reason I'll be released is the same reason you think...
我会被定罪的理由一样
I'll be convicted.
我的确跟一些…
I do rub shoulders with some of the most vile,
邪恶残暴的当代领袖称兄道弟
sadistic men calling themselves leaders today.
但其中有些人是我们敌人的敌人
But some of those men are the enemies of your enemies.
当你的老板是世界最大军火商
And while the biggest arms dealer in the world is your boss...
美国总统
...the President of the United States,
他一天运输的比我一年还多
Who ships more merchandise in a day I do in a year...
有时候在枪上留指纹很难堪
sometimes it's embarrassing to have his fingerprints on the guns.
有时候他需要我这种跑单帮的
Sometimes he needs a freelancer like me
送一些他不方便出面的货
to supply forces
所以，尽管说我邪恶
he can't be seen supplying. So... you call me evil,
但不幸，我是必要之恶
but unfortunately for you, I'm a necessary evil.
我想叫你下地狱…
I would tell you to go to hell.
但你已经在地狱里了
but I think you're already there.
很高兴跟你交易
Pleasure doing business with you.
多数人能出狱都很高兴
Most people are happy just to get out of jail.
我等人付钱请我出去，我不笨
I expect to be paid to leave. I'm not a fool.
今天他们需要我…
I know that just because they needed me that day
说不定下次我就变成代罪羔羊
didn't mean they wouldn't make me a scapegoat the next.
但我又回来重操旧业了
But I was back, doing what I do best.
送雨伞去萨哈拉沙漠？
Umbrellas to the Sahara?
阳伞
Sun umbrellas.
你知道谁将坐拥地球？
You know who's going to inherit the Earth?
军火商
Arms dealers.
因为其他人都在战争中丧生
Because everyone else is too busy killing each other.
让我告诉你活命的秘诀
That's the secret to survival.
千万别跟战争有所瓜葛
Never go to war.
更别把自己赔了进去
especially with yourself.
本片根据真实事件改编
虽然军火走私方兴未艾
世界最大的武器供应者仍是
美、俄、法、英、中
五个联合国常任理事国